Peter de Oliveira

+1 514 512 6184 deopeter@gmail.com

Peter de Oliveira has been working for seven years in visual merchandising, visual store experience, and store design.

During this time, he opened several stores, including flagship doors. Equally, he lead and developed staff toward achieving successful financial results.

His academic background has been geared toward creative direction, majoring in fine arts and focusing on architecture and interiors, technology and new media.

Peter designs store experience strategies to strengthen brand identity, pairing creativity with analytical business rigour.

Oualifications

Fluent in English, Portuguese, and Spanish; intermediary French.

Proficient in: Microsoft Office Suite; Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, and Premiere; Final Cut; Audacity; SketchUp and Layout; Rhinoceros.

Skilled in: art direction; store design; window displays; interior styling; sourcing design elements; trend analysis; visual merchandising; project management.

Education

BFA, Intermedia · Fine Arts, Concordia University, 2018

Advertising, OCAD University, 2011-12

Publications

"If Walls Could Talk," in The One-Hour Spatial Residency (Pouf! Art + Architecture: Montreal, 2015), documenting an installation at the Maison de l'architecture du Quebec.

References

Provided upon request.

Work Experience

Club Monaco, Ralph Lauren Corporation Montreal Flagship

SENIOR VISUAL STORE EXPERIENCE MANAGER, 2013-15

Managed new store opening, remodel, and real estate relocation process.

Lead and directed in-store, all-brand creative and visual merchandising initiatives, including client events, and monthly store-set installations.

Monitored and compiled business reports, analyzed in relation to product performance.

Completed current and historical analysis to support recommendations and decisions for product allocation.

Responsible for developing and overseeing a team of visual associates, visual supervisors, and freelancers. Supported the opening and set-up of Global New York Flagship and Toronto Flagship.

Regularly oversaw Ottawa store special set-ups and corporate visits.

Club Monaco • Les Cours Mont-Royal MEN'S SHOP VISUAL STORE EXPERIENCE MANAGER. 2011-13

Responsible for translating brand aesthetic to all aspects of the visual concept of men's shop.

Managed and conceived window changes. Trained and supported store management in planning and supervision of store flips and floor sets.

Coached and trained in-store visual staff and store teams regarding environment expectations.

Provided necessary feedback to corporate and field visual teams to drive business through visual merchandising opportunities.

Sourced visual props and greenery for interior space and window displays.

H&M • Bloor St., Toronto VISUAL MERCHANDISER, 2007-11

Followed brand-specific visual merchandising standards while providing up-to-date, consistently changing visual displays.

Supported opening of flagship stores in Vancouver, Calgary, and Montreal.